froala.com 2019-04-27

# Privacy Policy | Froala

Last Modified Date: **October 25, 2018**

Froala Labs SA ("Froala") is committed to respecting and protecting the privacy of our customers, partners, webinars attendees and website visitors. Specifically, we do not sell, rent or trade email lists with other companies for marketing purposes. In this Privacy Statement we describe Froala's privacy practices in relation to the use of Froala Website (as defined below) and the related applications, services, products and programs offered by Froala (collectively, "Services"), as well as individuals' choices regarding use, access and correction of personal information.

If you have questions or complaints regarding Froala's Privacy Statement or associated practices, please contact us at [legal@froala.com](mailto:legal@froala.com).

## 1\. Website covered

This Privacy Statement covers the information practices, including how Froala collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide to its website (the "Froala Website").

## 2\. Collection of Personal Information

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify you, such as, your name, title, phone number, email address, or mailing address.

In general, you can browse our website without giving us any personal information. We use web analytics software to analyze traffic to this web site in order to understand our customer's and visitor's needs and to continually improve our site for them. This software collects only anonymous, aggregate statistics. For example, we do not tie a specific visit to a specific IP address.

If you want to subscribe to a periodic communication such as a newsletter, we ask you to simply provide your business email address ("Optional Information"). Additional activities on our site may require you to be registered, for example, to read a white paper, download trial or free software, when you express an interest in obtaining additional information about the Services or register for an event. As part of the registration process, we may ask you for additional personal information, such as name, Froala name, address, phone number, and email address ("Required Information"). We use that information for several general purposes: to tell you about products and services if you so request, to fulfill your request, to contact you if we need to obtain or provide additional information; to verify the accuracy of our records, to contact you regarding customer satisfaction surveys.

For our downloadable software products, as part of the Required Information, on installation and execution, some of our products may send Froala certain information, including product version, product edition, and information about the operation system and/or environment where the product is installed. Solely for our software as a service products, as part of the Required Information and in order to provide the Services to you, we store all the content you provide, including but not limited to accounts created for team members, files, pictures, project information, and any other information that you provide to the Services you use. Even though Froala stores these data as part of its Services to you, Froala does not have access or collect such data. We may also collect data about usage of the software. This may include, but is not limited to, numbers of users and groups, frequency and size of attachments, actions invoked in the product, IP addresses used to access the service, operating environment, and other interactions with product features. This information may be analyzed for security and auditing purposes.

When purchasing Services or registering for an event, Froala may also require you to provide your billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number ("Billing Information"). Some activities require additional personal information. For example, to fulfill online orders for products, we require you to enter credit card information, and you have the option to provide a separate shipping address. When visitors of Froala Website apply for a job with Froala, Froala may also require you to submit additional personal information as well as a resume or curriculum vitae ("Applicant Information"). Froala may check for license validation and software updates for some of its products. Required Information, Optional Information, Billing Information, Applicant Information and any other information you submit to the Froala through the Services or information provided to you by the Froala through your use of the Services (e.g. license key) are referred to collectively as "Data".

As you navigate Froala Website, Froala may also collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons. Website Navigational Information as defined in Section 7 below, includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol ("IP") address, and the actions you take on Idera's web pages viewed and the links clicked). For additional information about the collection of Website Navigational Information by Idera and others, please see Section 7 below.

## 3\. Use of Personal Information

Froala uses Data about Froala's customers to perform the Services requested. For example, if you fill out a "Download Froala Editor" Web form, Froala will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in the Services. In addition, the Froala may use Data where it believes, in our sole judgment, to protect our rights and interests, for example to check for license validation either using the license key or your account details. Some software products can also use license information to inform you of the availability of applicable updates. 

Froala also uses Data about webinars attendees to plan and host corporate events, host online forums and social networks in which event attendees may participate, and to populate online profiles for webinars attendees on Froala Website. Additional information on Froala's privacy practices with respect to Data about webinars attendees may be found in additional privacy statements on the event Websites, as the case may be.

Froala may also use Data about customers and webinar attendees for marketing purposes. For example, Froala may use information you provide to contact you to further discuss your interest in the Services and to send you information regarding Froala, its affiliates, and its partners, such as information about promotions or events.

Froala may also receive information about customers and attendees from other sources, including third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this information with Data we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and create more tailored advertising to provide products and services that may be of interest to you.

Froala uses credit card information solely to collect payment from prospective customers and attendees.

Froala uses Website Navigational Information to operate and improve Froala Website. Froala may also use Website Navigational Information alone or in combination with Data about customers and Data about webinar attendees to provide personalized information about Froala. For additional information about the use of Website Navigational Information, please see the Section 7 below.

## 4\. Disclosure of Personal Information

### Business Partners.

From time to time, Froala may partner with other companies to jointly offer products, services or programs (such as webinars or downloadable content) such as our channel partners to fulfill product trials and information requests, and provide customers and prospective customers with information about Froala and its products. To do this, we may pass your information to them for that purpose only, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. Froala does not share Data about the Froala attendees with business partners unless: (1) you specifically opt in to such sharing via an event registration form; or (2) you attend a Froala event and allow the Froala or any of its business partners to scan your attendee badge. If you do not wish for your information to be shared in this manner, you may choose not to opt in via event registration forms and elect not to have your badge scanned at Froala events. If you choose to share your information with business partners in the manners described above, your information will be subject to the business partners' respective privacy statements.

Froala sometimes hires vendor companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering items, sending postal mail, providing technical support, and processing event registrations. We provide those companies only the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

### Third Parties.

Section 7 of this Privacy Statement, Website Navigational Information, specifically addresses the information we or third parties collect through cookies and web beacons, and how you can control cookies through your Web browser. We may also disclose your personal information to any third party with your prior consent.

### Service Providers.

Froala may share Data about Froala website visitors, customers and webinar attendees with Froala's contracted service providers so that these service providers can provide services on our behalf. These service providers are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide the requested services to us. Without limiting the foregoing, Froala may also share Data about Froala website visitors, customers and webinar attendees with Froala's service providers to ensure the quality of information provided, and with third–party social networking and media websites, such as Facebook, for marketing and advertising on those websites. Unless described in this Privacy Statement, Froala does not share, sell, rent, or trade any information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

### Billing.

Froala uses a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use Billing Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on Froala's behalf.

### Froala Affiliates.

Froala may share Data about the Froala's customers with other companies in order to work with them, including affiliates of the Froala corporate group. For example, Froala may need to share Data about Froala customers with other companies within the Froala corporate family for customer support, marketing, technical operations and account management purposes. The data protection laws in these countries may be more or less extensive than laws in the country in which you are located. However, Froala and its offices and affiliates are governed by this Privacy Statement and will use your personal information only as set forth in this Privacy Statement.

### Compelled Disclosure.

Froala may also disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in connection with a sale, merger, transfer, exchange or other disposition (whether of assets, stock or otherwise) of all or a portion of a business of Froala and/or its subsidiaries or to (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process served on Froala or this website; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Froala and this website; (3) enforce its agreements with you, or (4) act in urgent circumstances to protect personal safety or the public.

## 5\. Children and Privacy

Froala Website does not offer information intended to attract children. Froala does not knowingly solicit personal information from children under the age of 16.

## 6\. Security of Personal Information

When you submit any form requiring registration, we use a secure server. The secure server software (SSL) helps protect your information as it travels over the Internet by encrypting that information before it is sent to us. We have also implemented industry-standard security mechanisms and procedures to protect data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

## 7\. Use of Cookies

### Cookies, Web Beacons and IP Addresses.

Froala uses commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons, to collect information as you navigate Froala Website ("Website Navigational Information"). As described more fully below, we and our partners use these cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer Websites and Services, track users' movements around our Websites and Services, serve targeted advertisements and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. This section describes the types of Website Navigational Information used on Froala Website and Services, and how this information may be used.

### Log Files, IP Addresses, URLs and Other Data.

As is true of Froala Website, we gather certain information automatically to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer Froala Website and Services. This information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), device and application identification numbers, your location, your browser type, your Internet service provider and/or mobile carrier, the pages and files you viewed, your searches, your operating system and system configuration information, and date/time stamps associated with your usage. Due to Internet communications standards, when you visit or use Froala Website and Services, we automatically receive the URL of the website from which you came and the website to which you go when you leave our Website. This information is used to analyze overall trends, to help us improve our Websites and Services, to track and aggregate non-personal information, and to provide the Websites and Services. For example, Froala uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which customers and website visitors navigate the Froala Website. Froala also collects IP addresses from customers when they log into the Services as part of Froala's "Identity Confirmation" and "IP Range Restrictions" security features.

### Cookies

Froala uses cookies to make interactions with Froala Website easy and meaningful. When you visit Froala Website, Froala's servers send a cookie to your computer or device. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify you; they merely recognize your Web browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to Froala, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening an account, or filling out a Web form (such as a "Request a Demo" or a "Request a Quote" Web form) or have previously identified yourself to Froala, you remain anonymous to Froala.

Froala uses cookies that are session-based and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer or device when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer or device after you close your browser or turn off your computer. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on Froala Website or Services.

The following sets out how Froala uses different categories of cookies.

#### _Required Cookies:_

Required cookies enable you to navigate Froala Website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website and using Froala Services. If you have chosen to identify yourself to Froala, Froala may place on your browser cookies containing an encrypted, unique identifier. These cookies allow Froala to uniquely identify you when you are logged into Froala Website and Services and to process your online transactions and requests. 

#### _Functionality Cookies:_

Functionality cookies allow Froala Website and Services to remember information you have entered or choices you make (such as your username, language, or your region) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies also enable you to optimize your use of Froala Website and Services after logging in. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize.

Functional cookies may also be used to improve how Froala Website and Services function and perform, to enhance and customize your interactions with Froala, and to help us provide you with more relevant messages, including marketing communications. These cookies collect information about how website visitors use our Website and Services, including which pages visitors go to most often and if they receive error messages from certain pages.

Froala may use its own technology (under Froala brand name or an affiliated brand name) or third parties to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from website visitors, attendees, and customers, to provide enhanced interactions and more relevant communications, and to track the performance of Froala's advertisements. Froala and its third-party partners may also utilize HTML5 local storage or Flash cookies for these purposes. Flash cookies and HTML local storage are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Froala also uses Flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on Froala Website and Services to personalize your visit.

#### _Targeting or Advertising Cookies:_

Froala sometimes uses cookies delivered by third parties to show you ads for Froala products and services that we think may interest you on any devices you may use and to track the performance of Froala advertisements. For example, in these cases, cookies remember information such as which browsers have visited Froala Website. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after Froala receives it. If Froala is using one of its own cookie-related products on our own Website, then a cookie related to ads may appear on our Website under Froala or one of our affiliated Froala's name.

Froala also contracts with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information from Web beacons (see below) on Froala Website and Services, from emails, and on third-party websites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time and across different sites or other online services by collecting Website Navigational Information through automated means, including through the use of cookies. These technologies may recognize you across the different devices you use, such as a desktop or laptop computer, smartphone or tablet. Third parties use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other websites or mobile applications on any of your devices. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. Third parties, with whom Froala partners to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.

#### _Do Not Track._

Currently, various browsers — including Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari — offer a "do not track" or "DNT" option that relies on a technology known as a DNT header, which sends a signal to websites' visited by the user about the user's browser DNT preference setting. Froala does not currently commit to responding to browsers' DNT signals with respect to Froala Website, in part, because no common industry standard for DNT has been adopted by industry groups, technology companies or regulators, including no consistent standard of interpreting user intent. Froala takes privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will make efforts to continue to monitor developments around DNT browser technology and the implementation of a standard.

## 8\. Links to Other Websites and Public Forums

Our Website contain links to information on other websites. We do not have any control over these other websites, and therefore we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide while visiting those websites. Those websites are not governed by this Privacy Statement, and if you have questions about how a website uses your information, consult that website's privacy statement. Portions of this website may also make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to visitors. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information.

## 9\. International transfer of information collected

Froala primarily stores Data about Froala's customers and Data about webinars attendees, if applicable, in the United States. To facilitate Froala's global operations with its parent company, Idera, Inc., and its affiliated companies, Froala may transfer and access such information from around the world, including form other countries in which Froala has operations. A list of Froala's parent company and affiliated companies global offices is available at <http://www.ideracorp.com/contactus>. This Privacy Statement shall apply even if the Froala transfers Data about Froala customers or Data about attendees to other countries.

## 10\. Accessing, Updating and Correcting Your Personal Information

Froala may retain your information for a period of time consistent with the original business purpose of collection. For example, we may retain your information during the time in which you have an account to use our Website or Services and for a reasonable period of time afterward. We may also retain your information during the period of time needed for Froala to pursue our legitim business interest, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

You may request to review, correct, delete or otherwise modify any of the personal information that you have previously provided to us through Froala Website and Services. If you have registered for an account with Froala, you may generally update your user settings, profile, organization's settings or event registration by logging into the applicable website or Services with your username and password and editing your settings or profile. For other requests to access, correct, modify or delete your Data, please email [compliance@froala.com](mailto:compliance@froala.com) and we will assist you. Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be addresses within a reasonable timeframe.

## 11\. Unsubscribe

You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of Froala's marketing emails. Additionally, you may or by contacting us at any time.

## 12\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

Froala reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement from time to time. Froala will provide notification of the material changes to this Privacy Statement through Froala Website at least thirty (30) days prior to the change taking effect.

## 13\. Contacting us.

Questions about this Privacy Statement or the information practices of Froala Website and Services should be directed to our privacy team by emailing us at [compliance@froala.com](mailto:compliance@froala.com) or by mailing us at:

Froala Labs SRL  
Attn: Legal Department  
sos. Bucuresti-Ploiesti, Nr. 19-21, Biroul NR. R.4, Et. 6  
Bucharest, 013682  
Romania
